<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jaredhanson.me/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jaredhanson.me/feed.atom"/>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.jaredhanson.me/2023/10/27/hello/</id>
    <title>Hello</title>
    <link href="https://www.jaredhanson.me/2023/10/27/hello/"/>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who is passionate about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_identity&quot;&gt;digital identity&lt;/a&gt;,
I’ve often lamented the fact that my own online presence is quite fragmented,
scattered across various social networks.  I’m going to consolidate my
existence here on this site, where I’ll share my thoughts and connect with
others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously published a (long since defunct) personal blog during the rise of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0&quot;&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, a time filled with excitement
about building technology that empowers and connects people.  This was a
formative time for me and my career, where I became immersed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenID&quot;&gt;OpenID&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OAuth&quot;&gt;OAuth&lt;/a&gt;, and the broader issues of
identity, security, and privacy on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the nearly two decades since, the principles of Web 2.0, along with the
simultaneous rise of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing&quot;&gt;cloud&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_computing&quot;&gt;mobile&lt;/a&gt; computing, have
reshaped how society interacts.  While, in my opinion, the impact has been
positive, it is also evident that the way the technology has been applied has
fallen short of delivering on its promises.  Those shortcomings have led people
to look for alternative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a recent trend of people &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&quot;&gt;rediscovering&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ar.al/2020/08/07/what-is-the-small-web/&quot;&gt;advocating&lt;/a&gt; for, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://benhoyt.com/writings/the-small-web-is-beautiful/&quot;&gt;building&lt;/a&gt; what has
become known as the “small web.&amp;quot;  A new &lt;a href=&quot;https://kagi.com/&quot;&gt;search engine&lt;/a&gt; is
even &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kagi.com/small-web&quot;&gt;differentiating&lt;/a&gt; based on this movement.
This trend harkens back to the even earlier &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0#Web_1.0&quot;&gt;Web 1.0&lt;/a&gt;
era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some of this might be dismissed as retro-nostalgia, there’s a parallel
trend of people building next generation technology under the auspices of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web3&quot;&gt;Web3&lt;/a&gt;.
These projects take a more disruptive approach, relying on blockchains and
recent advances in cryptography to give people more control.  Even in the middle
of (yet another) &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/10/02/web3-venture-funding-q3/&quot;&gt;crypto winter&lt;/a&gt;,
more projects are being launched every week, adding to a list that is already
too long to enumerate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some people in each of these factions express dissent at both the current
state of affairs and its associated technology, I don’t share that view.
Rather than supplanting each other, as the version numbering notation might
suggest, the technology from each of these eras is symbiotic - better if it
coexists.  And while corporate-controlled platforms have become overwhelmingly
dominant, connecting with businesses and trusted third parties is crucial even
when individuals are given more control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a perspective that now spans three generations of web technology, I’m
going to use this space to explore what&amp;#39;s next, continue building for today, and
reflect on the past.  I hope the insights will help create better technology
that works better for everyone.  If you are interested, I hope you’ll join me.
Let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
